[Music]
hey guys so in this video I'll be
showing you how to achieve a look that
I'm wearing right now I was planning to
do a cut crease so what is it cut crease
the first thing that comes to my mind is
the winked cut crease this is my idea of
a cut crease I guess so I wanted to do
something like that but I realized that
I've already done couple of looks like
that on my youtube channel and on
Instagram I wanted to do something
different but I still wanted it to be a
cut crease so I decided to do the half
cut crease and I think that it's such a
pretty little tough cut crease means
that I'm cutting just the inner half of
the eyelid which is super cool so I hope
you guys like it and if you do please
don't forget to give this video a thumbs
up and subscribe to my channel if you
haven't already and yeah let's go and
start it now alrighty guys so I'm going
to start off with an eyeshadow by
Anastasia Beverly Hills it's
code-breaking and with the morphe and
5:05 i will apply it in my crease and
that's going to be my first transition
color now I want to build up the colors
in the crease so I'll use couple of
shades there and you know I'm just using
circular motions to make sure that
everything is nice and blended
taking one more eyeshadow buy us a
Beverly Hills it's a little bit darker
than that shade that I just applied the
crease and I'm switching to a smaller
blending brush this is the morphe y 18
I'll use it to apply that eyeshadow in
the crease but I'll keep it a little bit
lower than that previous shade that I
applied so you want to load your brush
with product and you want to place it
first right here in the outer corner of
the crease and then slowly work your way
towards the inner corner you want to
bring it all the way to the inner corner
and once you have almost nothing left on
the brush you can bring it to the brow
bone up here ladies but here is a trick
see that here in the inner half of my
eye I bring the eye shadows all the way
up to the brow bone but right here I
keep them a little bit low I didn't take
them on the brow bone so that's kind of
tricky and remember that the I show that
you bring all the way up to the brow
here it doesn't have to be too dramatic
so don't add any extra product there
just whatever you have on the brush
bring it up here and I'm going to
explain you why we're doing that in a
while just be patient next up I'm going
to apply this very warm red brick color
again by anastasia beverly hills it's
called blazing and I'm switching to even
smaller brush now you can tell that the
further we go with this look I'm
switching to smaller brushes that's
because I want to be more precise when
you're working with darker colors you
want to be precise because it can get
messy very quickly so taking that
eyeshadow on the morphe and 5:07 and i
will apply it in the outer corner of my
eye gonna keep it in the outer third
there are also very slightly bring it in
my crease
switching to the previous blending brush
that I use I would just make sure that
all the harsh lines are blended and
everything looks nice and smooth that's
mainly for the crease I'm not really
worried about this area right here and
now I'll go ahead and cut that crease
this is a very exciting part as you can
tell from the title of this video this
is going to be a half cut crease which
means that we're going to cut the crease
but just in the inner half of the eye so
I'll take a makeup wipe and what I'm
gonna do is I'm going to clean up that
inner half a little bit there it doesn't
have to be perfect I'm just preparing it
for the concealer that it's coming up
next and I'm doing that because
sometimes when you apply concealer on
top of some eyeshadows they actually
live like mixing together and it looks
very muddy which is not nice so I want
to avoid that that's why I'm first
cleaning it up with a makeup wipe and
then I'll go ahead and use some
concealer this is the Maybelline fit me
a concealer will do the job but you want
to focus on the brush the brush that
I'll use is by Sigma it's the F 70 and
it's a flat brush and it's very thin so
what you're looking for is a very thin
flat brush that's what works best in my
opinion so I'm taking the concealer on
that brush and I'll go ahead and clean
the crease now I want to be able to see
that cut crease when I have my eyes open
so I'll need to go a little bit higher
than my actual crease
[Music]
and if you have hooded eyes I suggest
you to go higher than your then your
crease just create up a fake crease
there and you also want to diffuse that
concealer into the shades on the eyelid
you don't wanna leave a harsh line
because it's going to be very difficult
to blend it out after we said it prevent
it from creasing I'll use this eyeshadow
again by makeup geek it's called fresh
and it's basically like almost white
eyeshadow the brush is again that Sigma
F 70 you really want to make sure that
you set it because it may look good now
but after a few minutes you'll start
creasing and it won't be nice anymore
the reason that I applied those
eyeshadows up to the brow here is
because if I cut the crease and there
wasn't any shadows in this area right
here I wouldn't have that contrast
between the the concealer and the
shadows so the cut crease it wouldn't be
that visible so now I want to diffuse
that concealer into the shadows and the
shadows into the concealer so I'll use
this eyeshadow here by makeup geek
it's called creme brulee and with the
Sigma e-40 one I would just like blend
them together I want to create a very
nice transition there now let's go ahead
and deepen up the outer corner I'll use
again an eyeshadow by anastasia beverly
hills
it's called fudge
grabbing again that Sigma e-40 one and
this time I use the eyes are called
blazing used to blend out that brown
shade it's all about blending now
smudging that burnt orange eyeshadow on
my lower lashes also adding some of that
deeper red shade okay so this look is
coming together I really like how it's
turning out
I was planning to add some shimmer on
this like naked area here but I love how
it looks now and I don't think that I
want to change it so let's go ahead and
do some winks now I will use my
Maybelline eye studio gel eyeliner and
the brush it's my favorite for eyeliner
this is a sigma yo six dramatic look
without any false lashes is like going
to your grandma's house eating all the
good things that she prepared but
skipping the dessert like no nobody does
that so anyway I'll go ahead another
pair by Iris beauty it's code athina'
and lastly I'll highlight inner corners
of my eyes and the brow bone with some
shimmery eyeshadow this one is by makeup
geek
it's called shimma shimma and this is
the page look guys I just throw some
lipstick I use the Too Faced melted
matte liquid lipstick in the shade it's
a gorgeous color I'm glad that I chose
to do a different cut crease than the
usual winged one and I love how it
turned out I will probably recreate it
with some glitter and some other shades
I think that a colorful version of this
would be absolutely stunning I love
doing colorful but I just need to get in
the mood for something colorful like I
need to have the idea in order to to
come up with something good so I will
wait for that idea to come and if you
guys have any suggestions and ideas just
let me know down in the comments so I
hope you guys enjoyed watching this
video and I wish you have a lovely
weekend just want to remind you to give
this video a thumbs up and subscribe to
my channel if you haven't already and
you can also follow me on my Instagram
Facebook Twitter and also visit my blog
all the links will be down in the
description box thank you guys so much
for watching and see you in my next one
bye
[Music]